# SANTIAGO DEVIA

437-256-3839

s.devia10@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/sdevia10

Linked-In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/santiago-devia Portfolio: https://sdevia10.github.io/my-portfolio/

Junior Software Developer graduated B.S. of Electronics Engineering, current post-graduate student of Software Development. 2 years of experience working in IT Sector with multiple Software. Highly interested in web development and data analysis. Great aptitude for problem-solving, coding in different programming languages, teamwork, fast learner with excellent communication skills.

## **COMPETENCES AND SKILLS**

Node.js	Python	Machine Learning	HTML CSS	Object Oriented Programming	
PowerApps	MySQL	MS SQL	Scikit-Learn	React	JavaScript
Bootstrap	RESTful APIs	PostgreSQL	C#	GIT	Java

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer Contractor – Trilogy Innovations**

January 2023 - March 2023

- Proposed and designed database model for Stock Market Application management and implementation of queries using MySQL.
- Creation of Restful API for Stock Market application using Python, and development of User Interface using React Library.

# **Team Member - Tim Hortons**

April 2022 - December 2022

Provided excellent customer service experience while efficiently working in a fast-paced environment.

# **Technology Analyst – Schlumberger**

January 2020 - December 2021

- Reduced used time in the creation of reports by developing a PowerApps and PowerAutomate App for the automatic production of reports.
- Consolidated and simplified information about the usage of company's software by creating documentation for ASP.net web application used by the company.
- Optimized workers' productivity by creating a Python WebApp that proposed the optimal distribution of workers shifts based on workload predictions obtained through Machine Learning Techniques.
- Resolved technical issues and inquiries with a 95% satisfaction rate by providing worldwide bilingual support to internal customers.

## **EDUCATION**

**Software Development and Database Management** 

Currently

Postgraduate Certificate – Lambton College Toronto

**Bachelor of Electronics Engineering** 

October 2020

Los Andes University – Colombia Award - High performance at National State Exam

ONLINE COURSES (Coursera) Full Stack Web Development MOOC Machine Learning MOOC

**LANGUAGES:** Bilingual English and Spanish. Intermediate French.

Santiago Devia